We...
How long do we have to be pitiful like this
until it's okay to be happy?
For pitiful people like us,
wouldn't it be better like this now?
Mitsuru probably...
[3-4-4 Minamisensu]
[Minami-Shinshu, Nagano Prefecture]
won't come back.
Hello, my name is Sakiko Seo.
Is Mitsuru at home?
Yes?
Sorry to show up so suddenly like this.
You're Mr. Sonoda, right?
Yes.
Nice to meet you.
I work at a children's welfare institution.
My surname is Hiraoka.
Oh, was it you who
used to take care of Azusa?
All right, please come in.
I was extremely shocked and saddened by this.
But I also knew that
she was married and had a child,
and that made me happy.
I'm very happy that
Azusa was able to meet someone
whom she wanted to marry.
Though it would be even better
if she was still with us.
Yes.
So today I've come to see her husband.
Hey, don't do that.
Oh, please feel free to have a seat.
Now there's a familiar face from the past.
- It's been a while.
- Thanks for stopping by.
- Is this about Azusa?
- Yes.
- I said hello to her husband.
- Ah, I see.
Did you know?
She was married and had a child.
I was surprised. Azusa...
Yes.
About that child...
Hello, Chizuru?
No luck, he wasn't there.
And the person living there
didn't know anything about Mitsuru either.
I wonder what that address was all about?
No, no, I'm by myself.
With that, I've done everything I can now.
I'm going to give up.
[Episode 5]
[Cream Cheese]
[Best before before opening: 2025/08/17]
It's been almost one year since the accident.
Mitsuru isn't coming back.
[Daikon 239 yen]
- Sakiko!
- Sho, no running.
- Ah, hello, Sho!
- Oh, sorry.
- Good evening.
Do you know what you're having
for dinner tonight?
Would you like to eat at my place?
- Is that okay?
- Yes.
I visited your place last week.
All right, then next time
you're welcome at my place again.
Okay, we can alternate.
Oh sorry, let me take that for you.
Thank you very much.
Sho, we'll be having dinner
at Sakiko's tonight.
- Yay!
- The 50% off sale is about to start.
- Starting now...
- 50% off, 50% off!
- All prepared foods, 50% off.
Great, great!
- What's there? What looks good?
- Which one do you want?
- What looks good?
- Which one?
Is it really okay to not tell Sakiko?
Understand. If that's the case,
then there's even more reason for me to go.
I'm worried, so...
Sunday, right? Please tell me the address.
Okay.
You know how there are some things
that you don't ever get around to washing
unless you really decide to do it?
- Like cushion covers, for example.
- Yes.
Coming here on Saturdays
has become a regular part of my routine.
If I were to take those covers off and
bring them with me every time I come here,
I think I'd be able to
wash them properly once a week.
They're being washed in there right now.
I see. That could be a good thing.
So do you really wash
cushion covers once a week?
Well, I do in the summer.
Oh dear, I don't wash mine even once a month.
What about your curtains?
How often do you wash those?
Curtains? No, I don't have
any memory of washing those.
I can understand that.
What is it?
Sho has an overnight stay
at his nursery school coming up.
For one night next Thursday.
I see. The parents seem
more nervous about it than the kids.
It'll be the first night I've spent
on my own for quite some time.
Ah, I suppose that's true.
I'm always alone, though.
But it's not so bad once you get used to it.
There's something about your job, right?
You're very busy on the third Friday
of the month, right?
- Yes.
- So Thursdays aren't that busy?
Are you usually free in the evenings?
- You mean Thursday evenings?
- Yes.
I suppose I'm busy.
Sorry.
No, no, there's no need to apologize.
Huh? Why are you apologizing?
All I asked was
if you were free on Thursdays.
Right, right. Sorry.
It's fine, really.
It's just that I've heard about
how busy your work is.
- Yes, exactly. Oh, sorry.
- No no, it's fine.
Ah, let me go get some small change.
Let's see, I can only use
1,000 yen bills here.
And it looks like
I happen to have that here...
I promised my teacher
I'd go swimming tomorrow too.
Oh, but tomorrow won't work.
I'll be taking you for a drive.
But we're just going there
to leave some flowers, right?
That's not all.
What really matters is how you feel about it.
If Mom's there, then I want to go.
But she isn't, right?
- Huh?
- Hey, hello.
- Goodbye.
Hey, wait. Hold on a second.
What is it?
What do you mean, "what is it"?
It's been almost a year now.
Is that all? Then why are you
all dressed up like that?
This is for... something else.
Then what about the shop?
- I closed it.
- Just for coming all the way here?
Yes. There's also something else
I need to take care of.
I see.
It's quite humid today.
Yes, it sure is.
- All right, then I'll be on my way now.
- Okay.
Oh right, isn't there supposed to be
a good soba restaurant around here?
Yes, there is. Want to go together?
I came here by car.
[Temporarily closed]
That other matter you said you had to
take care of, is it a funeral or something?
Yes.
Whose funeral do you think it is?
Well, I wouldn't know that...
Huh?
What is it?
It's not Mr. Seo's.
That was a shame.
Anyway, why were you there
leaving flowers for Azusa?
Please excuse me for a moment.
Hello, Sakiko? What's the matter?
Yes, that's right. Something urgent came up.
Is something the matter?
Ah, yes, that's right.
I'm sorry, I should have
contacted you before.
Oh, no problem. All right then,
talk to you later.
That was Sakiko.
Sounds like she went to
help out with the shop.
I hadn't heard anything about that.
Anyway, what were we just talking about?
Why did you come all the way out here
just to leave flowers for Azusa?
Well, I just came all the way out here
to leave a flower in respect, that's all.
And I haven't been able to
do anything for Azusa this past year.
I've been curious about this for a while now.
When you mentioned my wife,
you said that she was
a pretty and younger woman, right?
Her name... and maybe you even
went so far as to ask about her age.
But a pretty and younger woman,
or something like that...
I've been wondering if Mitsuru would really
talk about someone's appearances like that.
Mr. Seo...
You don't really know anything
about Mitsuru Seo, do you?
Well, I've never met him before,
but I think I have a pretty good idea.
Because I've heard a lot about him
from someone who does know him well.
I see.
Did you ever meet Azusa before?
Yes, she visited the shop.
What for?
Well, it is a coffee shop,
so she came to get some coffee, of course.
No, what I mean is, do you ask
each customer for their name
and their relationship with the shop manager?
Well, the day that Azusa came by the shop,
Mr. Seo happened to not be working that day.
She asked me if Mr. Mitsuru Seo was there.
When I told her that he wasn't working
that day, she seemed disappointed.
I was curious,
so I asked about their relationship.
And then she said that
on the third Friday of every month,
they chatted at the laundromat.
She heard that he worked at the coffee shop,
so she wanted to surprise him by stopping by.
That's all I heard.
When I asked her if there was anything
she wanted me to pass on to Mr. Seo,
she said no, it was fine.
And she also told me not to tell Mr. Seo
that she'd stopped by.
That's not like her.
Well, I only met her once.
You can't expect me to give
a really high-quality imitation.
Thanks for the food. I'm headed this way.
Hey.
Yes?
You've been in contact with Mitsuru, right?
Does he have any intention of coming back?
If so, would something change
for you as a result, Mr. Sonoda?
For example, feelings?
Anyway, I don't see any reason
why you couldn't get closer to Sakiko.
It's not like you'd be
causing trouble for anyone.
See you later.
The sewing machine... the sewing machine...
Stepladder...
[Stepladder]
Whatever, I'm going to the home improvement
store anyway, so I suppose it's fine.
Huh? What is it?
I've been thinking of
breaking up with my wife.
Huh? Really?
Yes.
Have you really given it some thought?
Are you sure that's okay?
Yes, I've made my decision.
I see. Got it.
Yes.
All right, then I think
we should break up as well.
No, I didn't say I was breaking up
with you, Chizuru.
I don't want to cause trouble for others.
Huh?
When I found out that
you were married, Takuma,
I thought about breaking up with you
just because of that.
I thought I shouldn't
cause trouble for your wife,
involving her in my love life.
But I heard that the stance
you two take toward your marriage
is that as long as everyone's okay
with this arrangement,
we can keep dating like this.
But if you only focus your feelings on me,
then this arrangement falls apart.
And that's no good, right?
Wait, just hold on a minute here.
I thought this would make you happy, Chizuru.
I suppose that's where
we have our differences.
Because you really didn't have any idea
about what makes me happy.
I understand the decision you made, Chizuru.
No way!
You've always had this slight
contempt towards me, haven't you?
Well, that was...
No, it's just that...
Does this mean your criteria for romance
is not causing trouble for anyone?
That makes sense.
Anyway, I can live on my own.
And I've totally given up on
the idea of having kids too.
And since that's the case,
when it comes to romance,
it should be fun and not something
that causes trouble for others.
That's really what it comes down to.
That's true.
What about you, Sakiko?
How are things going with that guy?
There's nothing going on between us.
He's just a neighbor I get along well with.
When I heard that nothing came
of that address in Nagano,
I thought that things would
eventually just settle into place.
I do think that he's a good person.
I see.
I always look forward to going to
the laundromat on Saturdays.
I even tried not to wear the same clothes
as I did the previous week.
I find myself being careful about doing that.
That's good, isn't it?
We also made a plan to go to
the home improvement store together.
That seems very relaxed and unpretentious.
I do enjoy being with him.
- Well, then shouldn't you...
- However,
it feels a little different from that.
You mean different from
how it is with Mitsuru?
He's still in my heart.
And unless he moves aside,
no one else can take his place.
Ah, yes, yes.
See you later.
Is it okay if we say goodbye here?
Will you be able to sleep
without having me around?
We won't be seeing each other again
until tomorrow, you know.
That's okay! See you tomorrow!
Hey, what about our fist bump?
- Hey! I'm here!
- Sho! Your bag with the cars on it!
[Important Information
Regarding Contract Renewal]
Long time no see.
- It's been a year now, right?
- That's right.
Sho's pretty amazing, being able to
go stay there overnight without crying.
Well, I suppose Sho's the only one
who's grown at all.
It's fine, you can go ahead
and throw that away.
You can put it out the next day
they come to collect burnable trash.
Is it still Mondays and Thursdays?
But I feel like if I throw your things away,
I might never see you again.
- So you haven't been able to throw them away?
- No.
Well, in that case, maybe it would
actually be better if you threw them away.
Otherwise, you might feel as if
you were having an affair, right?
- Huh?
- If I was always nearby,
and always staying here, well, you know...
By the way, tell that kid from
the coffee shop, thanks for the flowers.
It costs money to renew, so didn't
the timing actually work out perfectly?
Good luck with getting things
back to their original state.
Also, I think you might be
spoiling Sho a little too much.
You mustn't be afraid that he'll dislike you.
Just raise him properly!
Azusa.
I really am grateful to Miki.
I was happy to be able to
gain a sibling when we married.
It's fine. Why not just be here?
Oh, and I really don't like my mother-in-law.
I dislike her so much that
I've even come to dislike Ibaraki itself.
- Even though I'm dead, I still dislike her.
- Azusa!
But I put up with it
because I love you, Itsuki.
She may be a nasty old hag,
but she did still give birth to you.
- So I was even able to force a smile.
- Why, even now...
- I really was amazing when I was alive.
- am I still seeing Azusa?
Well, I suppose a bit of a push
in the right direction is necessary.
- When you're transferring...
- Why did you have to die?
I wanted to spend my life with you, Azusa.
Yes, that's true.
But it can't be helped, right?
I'm not around anymore,
so you can't make that choice.
Azusa.
My wording might be slightly off here, but...
Take care.
[Itsuki Sonoda -
Are you almost done with work?]
[I'm making Napolitan spaghetti.
Would you like to come over and have some?]
- Thanks for the food.
Wow, this is delicious! Incredible!
No, actually it's Cookpad
who deserves the credit for this.
After trying to make it for about a year,
I guess it's finally edible now...
No, it's really good.
- You really put a lot of effort into this.
- It's nothing.
Oh right, I also bought some
powdered parmesan cheese.
Here you go.
The contract for this place
will be up for renewal in another two months.
The timing is pretty good,
so I've also been thinking of moving.
Oh, that's right.
I'll help you with your move.
What about you, Mrs. Seo?
Well, I do wonder about living
all by myself in a house like that.
This is delicious.
Because he might come back?
Do you plan to keep living there by yourself?
Well, I don't have any plans
to move for the time being.
I'm going to ask a question that might be
so brazen as to be almost off-putting.
It's okay if you want to back out of this,
but please just hear me out for a minute.
Are you sure it would be backing out?
What is it?
I'm opening the parmesan cheese.
Would it be an option for me and Sho
to move in with you, Mrs. Seo?
Huh?
Would it be an option
for the three of us to live together?
No, that's not an option.
I see. Understood.
If we move, it should happen
before Sho starts school, right?
Children are more sensitive to changes
in their environment than adults are.
Yes, that's true.
I wonder what kind of layout would be best
for a parent and child living together?
Sunlight is also important too, right?
But since we'll be moving anyway,
maybe I'll just go ahead
and buy a drum-style dryer.
- You have a drum-style one, right?
- Hold on a minute.
- Yes?
- I can't just let this slide.
- What?
- What do you mean, "what"?
Why does it feel like
we've ended up living together?
No, it's fine if that's not an option.
- I just thought that it might be, that's all.
- Why did you think that?
Because I'm lonely.
Mr. Sonoda.
The thought of wanting to live with someone
just because of loneliness...
You aren't the sort of person
who would think about things so simply, right?
That's right. It's not like
I'd want to live with just anyone.
Oh, sorry. Let me take care of that. Sorry.
I suppose I am also lonely.
But I'm sorry.
Something like that,
I still can't think about it right now.
I'm sorry.
Soon it will be one year since the accident.
Do you think you could
give me an answer after that?
Huh?
I believe I just refused.
Please think it over.
When shall we go to
the home improvement store?
All right, I'll think it over.
[Café Hikouki]
- Thank you very much.
- Thank you.
What happened today?
Huh?
It's not often that
you ask someone for help, Naoto.
But it's not like it's especially crowded,
so I was wondering
if maybe something happened.
No, don't worry about it, it's totally fine.
I didn't have anything else going on anyway.
Okay, I'll be taking care of
some administrative work,
- so would it be okay if you do the cleaning?
- Sure, no problem.
- Also, the phone...
- Huh?
Could you answer it?
I mean, if anyone calls?
Okay, sure.
Hello, this is Café Hikouki.
Sakiko?
Yes. Mitsuru?
It's been a while.
Yes. Are you doing well?
I'm fine.
How about you?
It's been pretty hot out, but are you okay?
Are you eating well?
I am. How about you, Sakiko?
Yes. I'm eating well.
Are you sleeping well too?
I am.
Listen, I heard that it's possible
to get heatstroke even while sleeping.
So make sure to drink a full glass of water
before you go to sleep.
I see.
And as for the shop,
all the regular customers
are still coming as usual.
So I think things are going well,
though I was a bit worried at first.
Naoto's doing a very good job by himself.
And I also stop by to help out on occasion.
- Aren't you asking me where I am...
- The coffee that Naoto brews
has gotten really good.
Or why I disappeared?
It's now just about
as good as your coffee, Mitsuru.
It's just...
about the same.
About the same.
Why aren't you...
asking me?
Don't lie to me.
But if there's something
you don't want to talk about,
then you don't have to tell me.
I decided, you know, when we got married.
That brings back memories.
If you won't tell me, Mitsuru,
or if you don't want to tell me,
then that's okay.
I mean, if you wanted
to tell me, you would, right?
It's okay not to tell me anything
you'd rather not talk about.
Because we're still husband and wife.
Maybe that's just what
our family registry says,
but we're still husband and wife.
Yes.
But...
Yes?
But I'm sorry.
There is just one thing I want to ask you.
Because some things aren't just issues
between husbands and wives.
Yes.
Azusa Sonoda.
Why did you take her with you?
Sorry, but I had a look at your phone.
And I went to the address in Nagano
that was written down in your notes.
I didn't know the person who lived there,
and they didn't know anything
about you or Azusa.
That's what they said.
They didn't know anything.
But
since you'd written down
that address in your notes,
that was a place you wanted to go, right?
Well, whatever. It's fine.
You can go wherever you want,
and do whatever you want.
That's fine, but...
Why did you go together with Azusa?
You know, right?
There was an accident, and she died.
You know that, right?
Why did you go together with Azusa?
That...
If I don't know that,
there are people who will keep suffering
if they don't know what happened, understand?
There are people who haven't been able to
get answers to that this whole time,
and so they have to keep thinking about it.
The two of you went out together
without telling any of us,
I can pretty much guess
what kind of relationship you had,
but I want you to explain.
And please think of Mr. Sonoda too.
You know, right?
He has a kid too.
A 6-year-old boy who will be starting
elementary school next year.
Azusa left behind that kid,
she was a beloved wife,
and she died because of you.
Yes.
Why were you together?
Whatever, it's fine.
I understand.
That's what we decided, right?
You don't have to tell me.
Sorry.
Sorry to ask you that.
Sakiko.
What?
I'm glad you sound well.
Take care.
I will.
You take care too, Mitsuru.
I'm sorry.
There were some things I knew,
but I kept them hidden.
I mean, I...
I've been on Mr. Sonoda's side
this whole time, haven't I?
I was surprised by the things I was saying.
Yes.
I'm going home now.
I'd been thinking, the next time
I got a call from Mitsuru,
I'd ask him what I did wrong,
and what it would take for us
to go back to being husband and wife.
I'd planned to ask him that calmly.
But instead, the things that I said
were all said with someone else in mind.
- Hello.
This place is really beautiful, isn't it?
Apparently, Azusa used to be at this church.
That's good.
She can be at peace and sleep well now.
Thank you for your thoughtfulness.
Not at all.
Though I didn't think that
she would be coming back here like this.
Here, Sho, look straight ahead.
Good. And keep your back straight.
- This one too.
There are some over there too.
Shall we go take a look?
- Okay.
- All right.
So regrettable, isn't it?
Even though it's been a year now,
things haven't gotten any easier.
It's almost like being killed, isn't it?
That's not how I see it, though.
She had to go out with another man.
I find it hard to believe that
Mitsuru was dragging her around.
Maybe Azusa asked him to go along with her.
Or maybe she asked him if it was okay
if she went along with him.
To me, that would seem natural.
Yes, that does sound like
something she'd say.
Yes, it does.
She might have said something like,
"I want to tag along".
Yes, in that kind of vague way of speaking.
That's exactly the sort of thing
one might say when one's mind is made up.
Like, maybe she wanted me
to wash the bathtub.
Is that what she said?
Yes.
That's very cute, isn't it?
As people on Azusa's side,
I think it's best
if we just leave things at that.
That also saves me from
resenting people more than I should.
Right, being resentful is exhausting.
I don't want to be resentful.
I like this, it feels very stable.
Is your stepladder broken?
No, I've never had a stepladder.
I'd always leave high places
to Mitsuru or someone else.
One time I tried using a chair,
and ended up falling over.
- What?
- And since then, I've been a bit scared.
But,
I get the feeling that if I buy this,
that means he's really
not coming back, you know?
I understand.
But it's okay now,
so I'm going to buy it.
All right, I can hold it for you.
Thank you.
- This one.
- Ah, this one, right?
Also, I need some large trash bags.
Oof!
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
I managed to get it by myself.
Well done.
All right, I think I'm fine now.
Actually, he called me again.
Huh?
And I was able to talk to him a bit.
Even if he did run away, I can't hate him.
There's no way to explain it.
I guess it's just because I love him.
And so,
I thought that upon hearing his voice,
I'd completely lose my heart to him.
But actually, it was the opposite.
Even though I was talking to Mitsuru,
all I talked about was you, Mr. Sonoda.
It's different with him.
You're becoming...
someone else who's important to me.
During this past year,
I've been really glad
to have you around, Mr. Sonoda.
I was able to realize that.
But it does just so happen to be
that you're a man and I'm a woman.
Why are you saying it like that?
No, it's just that
with a man and a woman,
what it often comes down to is,
if that kind of relationship
is acceptable or not.
But even if we don't have
a clearly defined relationship,
isn't just being together
already good enough?
As long as we feel comfortable
around each other,
and as long as it's not
causing any trouble for anyone.
I also don't like we have to
have a clearly defined relationship.
Is it okay for us to just leave things
as they are, a bit ambiguous?
Maybe I'm feeling a bit
anxious or flustered. Sorry.
It's fine.
And as for moving here,
no matter how I think about it...
It would be quite sudden.
That was quite off-putting
for you, wasn't it?
No, but it did leave me feeling a bit shaken.
You really scattered that parmesan cheese
everywhere, didn't you?
I'm really sorry about that.
I'll buy you some more.
I'll start by getting rid of
Mitsuru's things.
As part of sorting out my emotions.
Alright.
The toothbrushes as well?
- Yes, please throw them out.
- Alright.
By the way, are you hungry?
Shall we order some pizza?
It doesn't have to be anything that fun.
But eating pizza alone
leaves you feeling kind of empty.
I don't think this can be worn either.
Your own stuff?
Looks like there's a lot of my stuff
to get rid of.
You met each other
- at a wedding ceremony, right?
- Yes.
Oh, right.
When we met, I was wearing this.
Wow.
That makes me curious.
An encounter significant enough
to become a password.
Password?
Wait, today is June 28th, isn't it?
That's right, it's today.
Huh? Wait, really?
You're actually giving away the password?
There wasn't anything there anyway.
What, do you want to hear the story?
It's a bit long.
Sure. And besides, I think this cleaning
is going to take a while anyway.
Okay, so it was the wedding ceremony
of one of my classmates from high school.
Ah, the pizza's here.
Please stay tuned for the rest of the story.
But it's still way too early in the story.
Coming.
I'm home.
Welcome back.